<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>iorgos.net</title>
    <link>https://iorgos.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on iorgos.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 22:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iorgos.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Femeile sunt Icoana curățeniei și a confortului</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/curatenie-reprezentata-femei/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/curatenie-reprezentata-femei/</guid>
      <description>Te-ai întrebat vreodată de ce mai toate reclamele ce privesc confortul, curățenia și armonia casei sunt cu femei în diferite ipostaze? Fie la duș, poate pregătindu-se de-o baie în cadă, relaxându-se sub un aer condiționat sau ventilator ori pășind grațios pe gresia curată a unei băi luminoase.
Serios, uite-aci niște exemple (fără a face reclamă cuiva), ba chiar unele decupate de pe Google Street View (str. Valea Cascadelor din București):                  La naiba, până și pe cutia unui ventilator ce-mi alină atmosfera pe timp de caniculă e aceeași idee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 17:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/cv/</guid>
      <description>The larger gaps in 2018 and 2021 onwards represent two long paternity leaves I took for my two sons. While taking care of that, I remained technically active thanks to my homelab, a GNS3 Academy subscription &amp;amp; studying for certification exams.
 Technologies I work with  Linux and Windows systems, both desktops &amp;amp; servers (including systems administration) Python (scripting &amp;amp; test framework development) BASH Jenkins CI/CD flows FreeBSD servers DHCP, DNS, web, e-mail &amp;amp; OpenLDAP/Active Directory servers Virtualization (kvm/qemu, Hyper-V, VMWare, bhyve)  Experience System Test Engineer – Enea (Jul 2020 → Feb 2021) (embedded-linux, python-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Telefonul</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/telefonul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/telefonul/</guid>
      <description>De fapt, nu mai este doar un telefon. Telefonul a devenit o funcție minoră, pierdută printre multe altele mai frumos colorate și mai dătătoare de dependență. Eclipsat de conveniența unei comunicări asincrone prin mesaje scurte private de orice emoție, nuanțe și ton, funcția (sau progrămelul/aplicația) „Phone” / „Telefon” pare că a supraviețuit grație vârstei producătorilor, care au prins așa ceva cu ani în urmă, când lumea nu se ferea de-a vorbi mai des.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Homelab</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/homelab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 17:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/homelab/</guid>
      <description>My Homelab Why on Earth would I even bother to build one? Because I really love playing around with various devices, testing out configurations and learning new stuff along the way. The thought of building my own “playground”/homelab occurred to me some years ago, but I’ve only just now got motivated enough to actually go ahead &amp;amp; build it (Thanks COVID-19!).
Since I live in a relatively small 2-bedroom apartment with extremely curious little boys, space constraints are a given (so are child safety “gadgets”, here and there).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sounds</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/sounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 17:51:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/sounds/</guid>
      <description>Sounds    Ever since I was a child, I loved sounds. My father used to be some sort of a music freak of the time, always on the hunt for music he liked. Hence, I was exposed to quite varied music like Vangelis, Jean-Michel Jarre, Pink Floyd, Led Zeppelin, disco music of the 80’s, some pop stuff and a lot of ambiental music. Over the years, I’ve played with computers, drums, guitars and synths (virtual and, lately, physical devices) in order to chase sounds and try to express myself in different ways.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying Microsoft Hyper-V Server 2019 without a Domain Controller</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/deploy-hyperv-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/deploy-hyperv-2019/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites  For fully managing the Hyper-V server remotely, you need to install Remote Server Administration Tools Download the Hyper-V 2019 ISO from Microsoft Rufus USB flashing tool A decent PC LOL  Installation Well, not much to say here. Pretty straightforward, just like a normal Windows installation.
Once the ISO is downloaded, stick an USB stick into your PC and launch Rufus. Select the ISO file you’ve just downloaded, make sure the USB stick is selected and check that GPT is used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Șoferii grăbiți și scaunele auto pentru copii</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/soferi-grabiti-scaune-copii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/soferi-grabiti-scaune-copii/</guid>
      <description>Această „pagină” din jurnal este, în fapt, o defulare (scrisă cu un mare nod în gât, la oră târzie din noaptea de după incident, stăpânit fiind de o încordare constantă combinată cu furie, regret și recunoștință). Trăiri probabil normale în urma unui șoc care nu a avut un final realmente tragic. Nu am pe unde vărs cuvintele astea, așa că le voi lăsa pe-aici, pentru posteritate. Poate experiența în cauză va fi utilă și altora, cumva.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quickly creating fixed sized files in Linux &amp; Windows</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/create-fixed-sized-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/create-fixed-sized-files/</guid>
      <description>Often times, while working as a Software Test Engineer, I encountered situations in which the software I was testing relied a lot on available disk space. If that wasn’t the case, surely it had a way to upload files to it (either through a WEB-UI or by sending them over a certain network protocol). So, I was either going to make sure the device/machine that program ran on would end up without any available disk space at a given point in time, or try to crash the whole program by feeding it large dummy or random binary files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ricing is the illusion of productivity</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/ricing-illusion-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/ricing-illusion-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Going &amp;ldquo;hardcore ultra-minimal&amp;rdquo; like others do might not suit you. And that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing.
Well, the title might seem a bit too generic, but bare with me because I’ll try to make things clear.
A bit of history I have been using Linux for quite a long time. I first touched it during highschool and ended up learning how to dual boot my PC with Windows 2000 &amp;amp; Red Hat Linux 5 (not RHEL, but the old distro).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mania culesului florilor</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/mania-culesului-florilor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/mania-culesului-florilor/</guid>
      <description>Am crescut prin cartierul muncitoresc Titan din București, într-o zonă dominată de blocuri cu patru etaje prin fața cărora se desfășurau grădini mari cu copaci variați și bogați (cireși, vișini, corcoduși, plopi, pruni, chiar și doi piersici), tufe de toate felurile și flori. Nu existau mașini și toată suflarea cartierului era unită prin acel liant nevăzut și mare Domolitor de Ego pe nume „sărăcie” (raportat la standardul din prezent, căci atunci nu percepeam lucrurile astfel).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aliases &amp; Profiles in PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/aliases-profiles-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/aliases-profiles-powershell/</guid>
      <description>Coming from a Linux background, I found myself looking for a way to define aliases in PowerShell. You know, like one does in bash, sh and the likes. PowerShell is one environment I believe people should understand and know how to use, at least at the bare functional level. It really does not matter if you prefer to use bash or tchor other UNIX CLIs. The truth is we live &amp;amp; work in mixed environments and it’s worth knowing how to orient yourself in a “mixed situation”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH key-based authentication in Windows 10 (using no password)</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/ssh-auth-windows10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/ssh-auth-windows10/</guid>
      <description>I found this solution here: []. Thanks a lot for that! Just adding this to my own “docs base” for personal future reference.
Working with Linux/UNIX machines, I rely a lot on SSH. Thus, not having to type passwords each time I open a new session is a great plus. Achieving this on Linux systems is trivial, since you have the ssh-copy-id command at hand. But, on Windows, that’s missing. Luckily, there is a (logical) way around that, instead of adding keys by hand in the remote server’s authorized_keys file (like I used to do).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Raspberry Pi cluster</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/building-raspberry-pi-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/building-raspberry-pi-cluster/</guid>
      <description>My first Raspberry Pi cluster Why? I did own some Raspberry Pi boards in the past and I found them quite appealing. With the launch of the 4th generation and the rise of the whole Kubernetes ecosystem, I decided to give it a try and learn how to build a low-powered cluster using these boards. Also, Raspberry Pi 4 offers a version with 8 GB of RAM and VMWare launched a &amp;ldquo;test version&amp;rdquo; for ARM64 CPUs, therefore I had to try it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compiling ‘suckless tools’ on FreeBSD</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/compiling-suckless-tools-freebsd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/compiling-suckless-tools-freebsd/</guid>
      <description>I wrote this tutorial for potential new users that want to try out new stuff and wish to expand their technical knowledge, but also because there are some commands and details around here I might forget some months or years down the line (for example, Xorg video driver configurations). The whole writing process was a very good opportunity for me to extend the CSS I used for my website and to try do to a better job at formatting tech/code/console-related text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When a tool becomes a drug</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/when-tool-becomes-drug/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/when-tool-becomes-drug/</guid>
      <description>Let’s take a second and imagine that you’ve just called in a plumber to fix a broken pipe in your bathroom. The guy arrives and starts unpacking all the things he will need in order to deal with your issue. But when he reaches for the wrench, instead of actually using it, he starts grining and looking at it as if he is experiencing true awe. Maybe he silently moans as he contemplates the handles and ruggedness of cold forged steel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cum mi-am găsit Nordul</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/cum-mi-am-gasit-nordul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/cum-mi-am-gasit-nordul/</guid>
      <description>Singurătatea este adesea acută atunci când ești înconjurat de foarte mulți oameni. În furnicarul unui mare oraș, relaționarea cu cei din jur devine foarte dificilă, iar construirea noilor prietenii tinde spre imposibil. Cu toții tânjim după autoizolare și ideea de-a ne cunoaște vecinii de bloc ne sperie, rămânându-ne doar împodobirea propriilor colivii cu vise la preț redus și țeluri fără noimă care nici măcar nu ne aparțin. Astfel, călătoria mea în căutarea sensului și apartenenței a luat naștere dintr-o profundă dezorientare, la un loc cu absența unei busole morale cu adevărat funcționale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Păcăneaua din buzunar</title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/pacaneaua-din-buzunar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/pacaneaua-din-buzunar/</guid>
      <description>Probabil că orice om care a folosit sau folosește un smartphone și mai are și cont pe vreo rețea socială (indiferent care ar fi aceasta) a avut de-a face cu minute bune sau chiar ore în care nu a făcut nimic altceva decât să scrolleze aiurea prin feed. De cele mai multe ori, utilizatorul pleacă de la impulsul de a verifica rapid ceva: vreo poză nouă de la un prieten aflat într-o călătorie, actualizări pe pagina vreunui eveniment, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://iorgos.net/posts/building-my-first-lab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iorgos.net/posts/building-my-first-lab/</guid>
      <description>The very FIRST “incarnation”    A discreet homelab, hidden away from curious toddlers&#39; hands
image
Network diagram This was also the largest one, of course. I was overly-enthusiastic and didn’t really have any precise goals. A Raspberry Pi cluster was also included, because I found the idea to be very fascinating and cool.
  1 x Atrust Intel-based thin client (an older, refurbished and fanless machine)
  1 x SuperMicro A1SAi mini-server based on the A1SRi-2358F motherboard, running VMWare ESXi (hosting an instance of pfSense that takes care of routing and LAN segments)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
